The Ice Alchemist?
氷結の錬金術師　ですか
Yes. He has infiltrated Central.
そうだ　彼がこのセントラルに潜入している
I'd like you to take command of his capture, Col. Roy Mustang.
ロイ·マスタング大佐
その捕獲の指揮を君に任せたいのだよ
Yes, sir.
ご命令とあらば
I'm thankful you were in Central at this time.
いや　君がセントラルにいてくれてよかったよ
I can leave this to you without reservation.
安心して任せられる
はっ
Oh, and that boy is here as well.
ああ　それと
あの少年も来ている
Utilize him to your liking.
存分に使ってやりたまえ
Führer President Bradley, by "boy", do you mean...
ブラッドレイ大総統
少年とはもしかして…
Yes. The Fullmetal Alchemist, Edward Elric.
そう
鋼の錬金術師エドワード·エルリック
Geez, that Colonel is a slave driver.
ったく　人使いの荒い大佐だぜ
And we'd just bought a train ticket to Lior, too. Guess we're going to have to cancel that.
せっかくリオール行きの切符買ったのに
キャンセルだね
Well, nothing we can do.
しょうがねぇ
Let's get this over with quick, Al.
ちゃっちゃと終わらせちまおうぜ　アル
All right, Brother.
うん　兄さん
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
There he is! That way!
行ったぞ　そっちだ
Stop! If you don't...
止まれ　止まらんと
Freezing and boiling. The elements of water.
氷結と沸騰　水の属性だ
Alchemy...
錬金術　はっ
That's pretty horrible.
ひでぇことするなぁ
Sacrifices are inherent when attempting something great.
大いなることをなすには犠牲は付き物だ
It's called the exchange of equivalences.
等価交換というやつさ
This and that aren't  the same thing!
そんなもんが等価交換のわけねぇだろ
Without a transmutation circle?!
錬成陣もなしに
You've got no time to be gawking!
見とれてる暇は　ねぇぜ
What?!
何っ
バカな
There's no way!
It should have boiled if there was a drop of liquid in it!
水があれば　沸騰するはずだ
You ruined my coat.
コートが台なしじゃねぇか
Auto-mail...
機械鎧
Genius alchemy skills that don't require transmutation circles...
錬成陣を使わない　天才的錬金術の技
...and an auto-mail as his right arm.
そして　機械鎧の右腕
お前が…
So you're...
...that Fullmetal Alchemist, Edward Elric!
鋼の錬金術師　エドワード·エルリックか
Wait... that's not you?
そっちじゃないのか
Umm... well...
えっと　僕弟のアルフォンスです
I'm Alphonse, his younger brother.
こんなチビが…
So this runt is...
Who are you calling short?!
誰がドチビじゃあ
To think that someone with the title of "Fullmetal Alchemist"...
鋼の錬金術師と呼ばれる男が
...would be such a small child...
こんな小さな子供だったとは
Quit calling me short!!!
ちっこい　言うな
Brother, I don't think he was talking about your height.
お兄さん　たぶん今のは背丈のことじゃないと思うよ
Even so, I can't forgive him!
たとえそうであっても許さんわ
As expected from Edward Elric, the Fullmetal Alchemist.
さすが鋼の錬金術師エドワード·エルリックさん
We appreciate your support.
ご協力　ありがとうございます
Oh no, I'm his little brother, Alphonse Elric.
あっ　いえ　僕は弟のアルフォンス·エルリックで…
うっし
Sorry to make you wait, Al.
待たせたな　アル
Let's go.
んじゃ　行くぞ
Geez, you're in such a rush...
まったく　せっかちなんだから
Steam...
水蒸気か…
Brother, he's...
兄さん　ヤツが
Damn him, using petty tricks!
くそっ　なめやがって
Looks like you underestimated your opponent, Fullmetal.
相手を甘く見てたようだな　鋼の…
Who the hell is he?
あいつ　何者なんだよ
That's why I told you to listen up earlier.
だから　説明を聞きたまえと言ったはずだ
But you claimed that you would be able to-
だが　君はそんなヤツさっさと…
Yeah, yeah, I get it. My mistake.
ああ　分かりました　悪ぅございましたよ
You should always listen to your seniors.
年長者の言うことは素直に聞いとくものだ
Yeah, yeah.
へい　へい
In any case...
さて…
His name is Isaac McDougal.
名前はアイザック·マクドゥーガル
He used to be a State Alchemist and was called Isaac of the Ice.
元国家錬金術師　氷結のアイザックと呼ばれた男だ
Used to?
元
That's right.
そうだ
イシュヴァール殲滅戦のとき
He performed outstandingly during
the Ishbal War as a member of our army.
我が軍の一員として活躍した
He gave up his title of State Alchemist after the war and became involved in a dissident movement.
戦後彼は　国家錬金術師の称号を返上し
更には反体制運動に身を投じた
Capturing him is a top priority.
ヤツの身柄拘束は最優先事項だ
But if circumstances dictate it, we may have to kill him.
場合によっては殺さねばならないだろう
I'm not going to kill.
オレは殺すのなんかごめんだ
Do as you wish.
好きにしたまえ
All we really want are results.
我々が求めているのは君の実績だけだ
By the way,
ところで
have you found any clues on how to fix your body?
体を元に戻す手がかりは見つかったのかね
Like you'd give us time for that!
そんな暇くれねぇくせに
Yo, Roy.
よう　ロイ
What a rough order, capturing the Ice Alchemist, eh?
氷結の錬金術師の身柄拘束とは
とんだ命令で災難だったなぁ
Or could this be a chance for a promotion?
それとも　セントラルご栄転のチャンスか
Whoa! Are you two perhaps... the Elric Brothers?
おおっ　もしかして君たちエルリック兄弟か
はあ…
Oh man, I'm quite honored to be able to meet the youngest State Alchemist.
いや　最年少の国家錬金術師に会えるとは
光栄だな
I'm Maes Hughes, a Lieutenant Colonel.
オレは　マース·ヒューズ　中佐だ
U-Umm... I'm Alphonse Elric, the younger brother.
あの…　僕は弟のアルフォンス·エルリックです
何　そっちが鋼の錬金術師だったのか
What?! That  one is the Fullmetal Alchemist?!
You'd better not call me a shrimp...
ちっこいいうなよ　ちっこい
Hughes.
ヒューズ
Yo.
おう
If you don't have anything to do here, go home already.
用がないなら　直ちに帰りたまえ
I will, after I do what I need to.
帰るさ　用が済んだらな
You guys probably haven't booked a place to stay yet, right?
君たち　どうせ宿決まってないんだろ
If so, stay at my place.
だったら　うちに来いよ
It's my wife, Gracia, and my daughter, Elicia.
妻のグレイシアと娘のエリシアだ
Elicia-chan~
エリシアちゃん
Ow, Daddy! Your beard hurts!
いや　パパおひげ痛い
Oh really?
そうかぁ　じょり　じょり
Rub-rub-rub.
Nooo!
いやん
Say hi to our guests, the Elric Brothers.
ほら　今日のお客さん　エルリック兄弟だよ
So tall!
おっきい
So short!
ちっちゃい
Elicia-chan, I'm Edward Elric.
エリシアちゃん…
オレはエドワード·エルリック
This is my little brother, Alphonse Elric.
こっちが弟のアルフォンス·エルリック
Understand? Little brother.
分かる　弟なの
If you're the older one, how come you're so short?
お兄ちゃんなのになんでちっちゃいの
Now, now, they're letting us stay. Calm down.
ほらほら　泊めてもらうんだからおとなしくして
Lemme go! Lemme go, Al!
Let's start dinner. Gracia is a great cook.
早速　飯にしよう
グレイシアの料理はうまいぞ
Whoa!
Come on, eat up.
さあ　食べてくれ
Itadakimasu!
いっただきます
It's so good! Wow, it tastes great!
うめぇ　おいしいです
Eat a lot, okay?
たくさん食べてね
Okay!
はい
Oh, Alphonse, you can't eat with that armor on, can you?
アルフォンスは　鎧着たままだと食えないよな
O-Oh, this is...
こっ　これは　その…
Al is... in the middle of an alchemy training right now!
アルは今　あの…
錬金術の修業中で
All right, Al. I'll eat for the both of us like always, okay?
よし　アル
今日もオレが２人分食うからな
Leave it to me, leave it to me!
Training~ Training~
任せろ　任せろ　　しゅぎょ　しゅぎょ
Central Prison
That's the funniest joke I've heard in a while.
最近　聞いた中ではいちばん面白い冗談ですよ
氷結の錬金術師と私が手を組む
Join forces with the Ice Alchemist?
Me, the Crimson Alchemist?
この紅蓮の錬金術師が
Kimbley, let's defeat Bradley
and the corrupt military, together.
キンブリー　共にブラッドレイを
腐った軍部を打倒するのだ
I know you've seen it at Ishbal, too. That hell.
お前もイシュヴァールでは見たはすだ　あの地獄を
You know what Bradley made us do.
ブラッドレイが私達に何をさせたか知っているはずだ
That's why you killed those officers, is it not?
だからお前は軍の高官どもを手に掛けたんだろ
Oh no, please don't misunderstand me.
誤解しないでください
I wasn't thinking of anything lofty like you are.
私はあなたみたいな高尚なことは考えていません
あいつらを殺したのは　殺したかったからに過ぎませんよ
The reason I killed them...
...is because I wanted to. That's it.
It's a shame, Kimbley.
残念だよキンブリー
It really is.
本当に残念だ
Thanks.
ご苦労さん
This is rare. You can't sleep?
珍しい
眠れないの
Yeah.
まあな
Should I take a guess?
当ててみましょうか
You were thinking about those two, weren't you?
あの二人のことを考えていたんでしょ
State Alchemists are called
the "dogs of the military" by the public.
国家錬金術師といえば
世間からは　軍の狗なんて呼ばれてる存在だ
When I think that he has to carry such a burden at such an age...
あの年で　そんなのしょわされてると思うとな…
Brother, are you awake?
兄さん　起きてる
Gracia-san's quiche was just like Mom's, don't you think?
グレイシアさんのキッシュ
お母さんのみたいだったね
Yeah, it tasted great.
ああ　うまかったよ
Really?
ほんと
Then I'd better add that to my
"List of things to eat when I get my body back".
それなら　体を取り戻したら食べる物リストに加えなきゃ
Yeah, you'd better do that!
おう　加えとけ　加えとけ
Brother?
兄さん…
Hmm?
It would be nice to get our bodies back to normal soon, wouldn't it?
早く元の体に戻りたいね
Yeah.
そうだな
Just one more...
あと一つ
With just one more, Bradley will fall straight to hell.
あと一つでブラッドレイは地獄に落ちる
報告によれば
According to reports, Isaac infiltrated Central Prison last night.
アイザックは昨夜　中央刑務所に潜入した
We cannot let the situation continue any longer. Make sure you seek him out.
事態は一刻の猶予もならない　必ず見つけ出せ
道路を封鎖し　あらゆる場所を捜せ
Block the roads and search everywhere.
見つけしだい射殺してもかまわん
You are authorized to shoot him on sight for all I care.
これは大総統令である
This is an order from the Führer President!
私も…　出る
I... will be heading out, as well!
Hurry, relief soldiers!
救護兵　急げ
死傷者５名
Five casualties so far. Report to headquarters!
本部に報告
This is horrible...
ひどい…
水蒸気爆発だ
It was a steam explosion...
水は急激に温度を上げると爆発的に膨張する
If the temperature of water is raised rapidly, it expands explosively.
人体は７０％水だからな
A human body is 70% water, after all.
急ごう
Let's hurry. We have to find that guy fast.
ヤツを早く捕まえないと
Yeah.
よし
There.
我が錬成をかわすとはさすがですな　アイザック殿
To dodge my alchemy... As expected of you, Sir Isaac.
その声　アームストロング
That voice... Armstrong!
いかにも
Precisely!
豪腕の錬金術師　アレックス·ルイ·アームストロング
The Strong Arm Alchemist,
Alex Louis Armstrong!
くらえ
Take this!
高圧の水はあらゆるものを切り裂く
High-pressure water slashes through a variety of things!
我がこぶしの前には　無意味ですぞ
It's quite meaningless against my fist, though!
少佐
Major!
危ない
Watch out!
水筒の水か…
Water from a canteen, eh?
Thanks, Al.
サンキュー　アル
追いかけよう　兄さん
We've got to go after him, Brother.
行くぞ　エルリック兄弟
Let's go, Elric Brothers!
はい　おう
Yes!
Right!
久しぶりだな
It's been a while, Ice.
氷結の
Roy Mustang...
ロイ·マスタング
いや　焔の錬金術師
...no, the Flame Alchemist.
残念だよ
It's a shame that I must fight a past comrade.
かつての戦友と戦わねばならないとは
Comrade? I do not have any friends.
戦友
私に友などいない
イシュヴァールにいたのは腐りきった軍とその狗どもだ
The only ones that were at Ishbal were the corrupted army and their dogs!
It's just fire, after all.
しょせんは炎　水には勝てぬ
It can't win against water!
Dammit!
くそ
よし　よし　よし
Good, good...
そこまでだ
That's it for you!
こんな路地で何をしていたか気になって戻ってみたら
I was wondering what the heck you were doing in an alley like this back then...
ビンゴだぜ
...so I came back, and bingo.
逃げようたってムダだよ
No use trying to run away.
Run? There's no need for that.
逃げる　必要ない
同時に　こんな錬成反応…
A simultaneous alchemy reaction... like this?
No way...
ありえない…
まさか　これは
Don't tell me... could this be...
賢者の石
The Philosopher's Stone!
何　大気中の水分を…
What?!
It's freezing all of the moisture in the atmosphere...
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric.
軍の狗　国家錬金術師よ
Dog of the military. State Alchemist!
Do you have any idea what this country is trying to do?!
お前はこの国が何をしようとしているのか知っているのか
Hell if I know! More importantly...
知るか
そんなことより…
知れば　私のやろうとしていることが分かるはずだ
If you did  know, you'd understand why I'm doing this!
I told you, I don't know!
知らねぇつってんだろ
All right, Al, good work!
よし　アル　よくやった
兄さん　この人の錬金術…
Brother, his alchemy...
ああ　おいあんた　賢者の石持ってんだろ
Yeah!
Hey, you!
You have the philosopher's stone, don't you?!
なんの話だ
What are you talking about?
言わねぇんなら力ずくで
If you're not going to tell me, then I'll make you!
Is this really the time to be blabbering nonsense?!
分かんねぇこと言ってる場合かよ
我がアームストロング家に代々伝わりし
A skill that has been passed down
the Armstrong household for generations...
We're leaving it to you, Major!
任せた　少佐
芸術的錬金法
Artistic Alchemy!
とくと見るがよい
Engrave it on your soul!!
なんと
What?!
何やってんだよ　少佐
What the hell are you doing, Major?!
いや　我輩は…
No, I...
氷の壁が…
The wall of ice...
つながっていく
...is connecting....
まさか　あの人
Could it be... that man...
セントラルを　いや　中央司令部を
...is trying to freeze Central...
...no, Central Headquarters?!
氷漬けにするつもりか
少佐
Major! Al and I will stop that guy.
オレとアルがあいつを止める
その間に錬成陣を
While we're on that, please take care of the transmutation circles!
壊すのだな
I need to destroy them, right? Got it!
あい分かった
キング·ブラッドレイ　今こそ我が氷結により
King Bradley! Now is finally the time for me to to send you to hell with my ice!
貴様を葬り去る
待ちやがれ
Now wait just a second!
邪魔くせぇ
Out of the way!
あちちちっ
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
兄さん
Brother!
遅い
Too slow!
アル
Al!
空の鎧だと
An... empty armor?!
You... established a soul on to a piece of armor?!
まさか　鎧に魂を定着させたというのか
腕を失い　弟は体が空っぽ…
Losing an arm...
...and the little brother is left without a body...
そうか　お前ら
I get it now. You guys...
禁忌を犯したな
...committed taboo, didn't you!
錬金術師最大の禁忌　人体錬成をやったんだな
The greatest taboo an alchemist can commit...
Human Transmutation!!!
アル　アルフォンス
Al!!! Alphonse!!!
くそ　こんなはずじゃ
Shit! This isn't how it was supposed to be!
ち…　畜生
Dammit!!! They took it away!!!
持っていかれたぁ
返せよ　弟なんだ
Give him back... He's my little brother...
Give him back... He's my only brother!!
返せよ　たった一人の弟なんだよ
お前　今地獄へ一歩踏み出したぜ
You... just took a step toward hell.
あきらめな　使おうにも水がないぜ
Just give up!
There's no water for you to use.
You've forgotten...
忘れているぞ　人体の７０％が何で出来ているか
...what 70% of the human body is made of!
兄さん
Brother!
お前らには分からないのだ　この国の姿が
You guys don't know the true face of this country!
Brother... Brother!
兄さん　兄さん
アル　あいつを追うぞ
Al, we're going after him.
なめたマネ…
Using little tricks like these...
しやがって…
やったか
Did we do it?
またか
Again?!
Don't you dare underestimate my flames!
私の炎を　なめるな
まったく　無能は雨の日だけにしてくださいね
Seriously...
Keep your useless days to rainy days only, please.
ブラッドレイ
Bradley!
覚悟
Brace yourself!
残念ですね
Too bad for you.
少佐　今だ
Major! Now!
Roger that!
了解しました
キング·ブラッドレイ大総統…
Führer President King Bradley...
おお　ご苦労だったね　鋼の錬金術師
Ah, good work, Fullmetal Alchemist.
そうか　君の助太刀ができたとは
I now have something to brag to my son about, that I was able to lend you a helping hand.
こりゃあ　息子にいい自慢話ができる
What, you've caught a cold?
なんだ　風邪か
そりゃそうとお手柄だったそうじゃねぇか
Anyway, I heard you were great out there!
オレは錬成陣を破壊しただけだ
All I did was destroy the transmutation circles.
The Führer President defeated him.
犯人は大総統が倒された
その大総統が　お前の手柄と言ってるんだ
And the Führer President is saying that it was your work.
なんだ不満か
What, are you unsatisfied?
Accept his words thankfully.
お言葉有り難くちょうだいしとけ
昔からいうだろ　年長者の言うことは素直に聞いとくもんだって
You've always said this, haven't you?
"You should always listen to your seniors."
結局…　賢者の石かどうかも分からずじまいだったね
In the end, we never found out whether he had a philosopher's stone or not.
ああ　軍の調査を待つしかないな
Yeah, we're going to have to wait for the investigation by the army.
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric, I heard you were hospitalized, and...
入院したと聞いて飛んできた
...I came here right away!
どれ　入院中のぶりょうを慰めてやろう
Now, how about I comfort you while you're bored out of your mind from being hospitalized!
心温まるだろう　この筋肉美
Don't they just bring warmth to your heart? These graceful muscles of mine.
遠慮するな　触っていいぞ
Don't be shy, now. You can touch them.
やめろぉ
Stop it!!!
そう　アイザックは死んだのね
I see. So Isaac died.
He was a human pillar, too. That's too bad.
人柱になれたのに惜しいことしたわ
で…　賢者の石は
And? What about the philosopher's stone?
Oh, so he used it all up.
使いすぎたのね
グラトニー　変なもの食べちゃダメでしょ
Gluttony, you're not supposed to be eating weird things.
Yeah, it's all going well in Lior.
リオールはうまくいってるわ
始まるわよ
It will begin soon.
もう　すぐにね…
Very soon.
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本语字幕录入：FAYFAY
リゼンブール
Resembul.
そこは少年たちが生まれ
The kind town where the boys were born and spent their childhood with their mother.
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs
母とともに過ごした優しい町
失った笑顔を求め
Seeking for that smile that was lost,
少年たちは禁忌を犯し
the boys commit taboo and witness the "truth".
真理を目撃する
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第二話　はじまりの日
Episode 2, The First Day.
旅立ちを決めたのは　自分の心
It was his heart that decided to step out into the world.